澄心委员会（三）
以这种方式在一个组织中工作需要很大的耐心。
It takes a lot of patience to be in an organization this way.
因为我们内心确实有要
Because we do have  in us is impulse
控制过程并“得到结果”的冲动。
to control processes and quotes 'get results'.
有很多咨询都会进入修正模式,
And the  fixing mode that a lot of consultants get into,
从表面上看，它在控制过程和
looks on the surface like it's doing a better job
获得结果方面做得更好。
of controlling processes and getting results.
我的感觉是，这往往是
My sense is though that is often an illusion
在短时间内被制造出来的一种幻觉，
that gets manufactured for a short period of time
之后一切又恢复原状。
and then things revert back to the status quo.
无论在组织里还是在这个世界上,
It takes more time in patients,
以一种问询的方式帮助
to be in that organization or in the world,
人们在镜子中看到自己，
in an inquiry mode which helps people
需要有更多的耐心。
see themselves in the mirror.
但是一旦人们看清了自己,
But once they've seen themselves,
这种转变更有可能
the transformation is much more likely to
站稳脚跟，持续下去，走得更远。
have legs to stand, to last, to make the distance.
在贵格会传统中，有一个伟大的故事，
There's actually a great story out of Quaker tradition
我很乐意告诉大家。
that I'd love to tell about this.
这个故事是历史事实，
Because it's historical fact and
我认为它见证了我想说的这一点。
I think it witnesses to the point I'm trying to make.
在美国内战爆发前一百年,
A hundred years before the Civil War was fought,
东海岸有贵格会教徒，
there were Quakers on the East Coast
像其他人一样他们拥有奴隶,
who like everybody else owned slaves,
这些人是农民，用奴隶来经营农场，
they were farmers and you ran a farm with slaves
而这就是当时的美国经济。
that was the American economy.
在贵格会教友团体中,
And there was among within that Quaker community,
有一个叫约翰·伍尔曼的人,
a man named John Woolman,
正如他所说的，上帝告示他，
who had it as he said laid upon him by the Lord
奴隶制是邪恶的，是道德上的错误。
that slavery was evil and moral wrong.
上帝召唤贵格会教徒来解放他们的奴隶。
And the Quakers, that God was calling Quakers to free their slaves.
伍尔曼把这个告示带到了当地会众的集会上。
He took this to his local meeting, congregation.
会众在公开对话中与伍尔曼进行理论。
And they wrestled with it in open dialogue.
但他们无法达成共识，
And could not come to consensus
对贵格会教徒而言必须要做的是：
which is what Quakers have to do,
他们不对结果投票,
they don't take a vote,
因为他们认为投票是暴力的，
because they think voting is violent
如果51%的人能告诉49%的人该何去何从,
if 51% can tell 49% where to get off,
这就是一种暴力行为。
that's an act of violence.
他们努力促成共识，
And so they labored with it trying to reach consensus
但却无法达成。
but couldn't reach consensus.
不过他们对约翰 · 伍尔曼说,
But they said to John Woolman,
“虽然我们自己还未开启明灯，
"While we don't yet have this light for ourselves,
但我们毫无疑问认为
we don't have any doubt
你对一些事情看得非常清楚,
that you're  seeing something very clearly,
只是我们还未看到。
we just can't see it yet.
因此，当你在东海岸
And so we will support  your family
贵格会朋友中东奔西走期间，
while you travel among Quaker Friends
传递信息、分享启示，
up and down the East Coast, delivering your message
只为废除奴隶制这件事情可以发生，
sharing your revelation for as long as
我们会照顾好你的家庭的。
it takes for some kind of outcome to happen.